[theme music playing]
[host] Let's all welcome
the Ardiente family!
[Emilia] You know, Camia Cruz,
if you're telling the truth,
then come out! Show yourself!
[Camia] Are you looking for me?
Well, Emilia. Are you stressed?
It's time for you to pay
for what you've done!
I swear no Ardiente will ever hurt
or abuse anyone again!
-[Julio banging cane]
-or abuse anyone again!
[Julio] It's her word against ours.
I'll see you in court.
[Emilia] We have to be united
against Camia.
You're right, I agree,
but on one condition.
Get rid of Raul! He's a threat.
-I don't trust you anymore.
-I'll change.
I'll earn back your trust in me.
Don't just promise. Do it.
[Julio] As for Camia Cruz?
She's nothing without
those witnesses she's hiding.
I swear I'll find where they're hiding.
[Julio] Make sure that each and
every one of those witnesses
regrets their decision
to go up against the Ardientes.
I want each of them to suffer.
-I'm okay, Mom.
-Be careful, Maria.
Text us as soon as you get back
to your aunt's house.
-Let go of me!
-[Raul] Your grandfather already knows
where Camia's hiding the witnesses
against the Ardientes.
[Ivy] If you'll keep believing him,
maybe I shouldn't trust you either.
It wouldn't hurt to take precautions.
[Ivy] Did you notice anything suspicious?
No, ma'am.
Tomorrow, more men are coming
to help with security.
All right, ma'am. I'll go back to my post.
Okay.
[line ringing]
Hello, Ivy?
Jepoy…
What's happening in
the Ardiente's mansion?
I spoke to Diego.
He said Raul tipped him
off that the Ardientes
know where the safe house is.
I don't want to believe Raul
because I don't trust that monster.
But Diego's right too.
It wouldn't hurt
to take precautions.
I'll handle it, Ivy. I'll find out.
And, Jepoy, if you can, plant
a surveillance camera for us.
So we can monitor…
the Ardientes' movements.
Okay, copy.
Thank you.
[Raul] It doesn't matter to me
if she'll never trust me again.
What's important is she's ready
for the Ardientes.
[unsettling music playing]
[Diego] Dad you might
get in trouble for this.
I'd rather get in trouble while fighting
than get in trouble while doing nothing.
But, why are you still there?
Thing is…
I can help Camia more if
I stay here with the Ardientes.
Dad, please…
Forget about Mrs. Camia.
I can't do that.
I love Camia.
And I know you don't understand…
but I'm begging you.
Don't ever leave her.
Always take care of her.
Protect her.
-But, Dad…
-That's all, bye.
Dad!
You traitor!
-Who was that?
-Wait!
-Give me that!
-Stop!
Give it to me!
[thuds]
There! You want that? Huh?
Do you still want it?!
I will find out who you're working with!
And both of you will suffer!
So, Miss Aguas has
returned to Poblacion Ardiente.
Yes, Mayor.
Did Mama go anywhere else?
No, Mayor.
Be sure to accompany her again tomorrow.
-Copy that.
-You can go now.
Mayor, it looks like you
were celebrating earlier.
Have you found a way
to silence that Camia woman?
I can help you.
What's it to you?
Your assignment
is to look after my mother.
I just wanted to help, Mayor.
I'm sorry for asking.
[tense music playing]
[car horn honking]
[Julio] After my TV appearance today…
people will definitely forget…
about how…
that Camia woman even existed.
And…
that'll only happen
if you do things as planned.
I promise you, Grandpa…
the rats will come out of hiding.
-That's what I want to hear.
-Okay, I have to leave now.
-Okay.
-I'll go with you, Mayor.
[Emilia] Oh, wait. Arnaldo…
are you leaving?
Is Madrigal going with you?
Why? Do you need him?
Yes. I just have to get rid of something.
Get rid of what?
Who could it be?
You know, Emilia,
nothing would make me happier…
if you're talking about Raul.
[Julio laughing]
This day couldn't have been more perfect.
Take care, then.
I'll go now.
Good luck, Emilia.
I better get going too, Papa. Bye.
[Esther] Why did they add more security?
I don't feel good about this, Edward.
Don't think that way, Esther.
They just want to protect us.
[Maria whimpering]
[phone vibrating]
It's Maria.
Talk to her.
Mom!
Dad! Please help me!
Edward!
-What's wrong?
-Our daughter…
-Please, save me!
-That's enough. Shut her up.
Hello?
If you still want to see
your daughter alive…
you'll come see me.
It's Maria.
Why? What happened to her?
[Maria crying]
Here.
[man] We didn't notice anything
suspicious last night, ma'am.
Everything was in order.
Thank you. Mom.
Why? Is there a problem?
It's nothing. Don't worry about it.
I want to know.
I spoke to Diego last night.
He said Raul told him
that the Ardientes already know
the location of our witnesses' safe house.
-What? How?
-I don't know, Mom.
But I asked for additional
security at the safe house.
[phone ringing]
Jepoy?
Ivy.
Listen to me.
The Ardientes are making their move.
They're planning something.
I think they're targeting the witnesses.
Madrigal!
Who was that?
I just checked on the house.
Let's go.
[suspenseful music playing]
Mom, I need to go to the safe house.
-I'll go with you.
-No need. Just stay here.
I'll call you to keep you updated, Mom.
Start the car. We're leaving.
The additional security staff
just arrived this morning.
Very good. Do they know
we're on high alert?
Yes, ma'am.
Make sure security is tight.
No one will leave this house
without my knowledge.
-Understood?
-Guard.
Have you seen Esther and Edward around?
Why?
We've been looking for them all day.
We checked the rooms
but they aren't there.
Check the CCTV footage now!
-Yes, ma'am.
-Hurry up!
How did this happen?
What do you plan on doing with him?
It depends, Aunt Claire.
Will you have Raul killed?
It depends on his answers.
You two, leave me.
Let me deal with Raul on my own.
[Claire] Let's go, Madrigal.
[door closes]
[ominous music playing]
[Emilia giggling]
[Emilia sighs]
Good morning, my dear husband!
Good morning!
Emilia…
What's the meaning of this?!
Why did you? Untie me, Emilia!
Why do you have a gun?
[Raul] Why?
Emilia…
-Well, Raul…
-What's this?!
Bad news. You can't get out of here.
Don't you play with a gun, Emilia.
[humming]
Where did you go?
Why did you escape?
Hurry up!
Maria?
-Maria!
-We're home, Maria.
Maria, where are you?
Where's our daughter?!
Where is she?!
Don't move! Stay where you are!
Stay where you are!
-You bastards!
-Where's our daughter?
[Maria] Mom!
-Maria!
-Maria, my daughter!
-Stay here!
-Maria!
-Stay there!
You bastards!
-What did you do to her?
-Maria!
-Mom!
You monsters!
[Raul] Emilia, stop this!
Let me go! Untie me right now!
For what? So you can escape
and see your beloved Camia?
-What's wrong with you?
-Sorry.
Emilia, let's talk about this.
No threats or tricks! Put that gun down!
Now, let's play a game.
Truth or dare.
-Emilia.
-I'll ask you a question.
Then, you'll answer it.
If you don't give me the right answer,
I'll close my eyes and shoot you.
-Emilia…
-Who knows where I might…
-…shoot?
Emilia. Emilia, you don't have to do that.
Let's talk about this. Don't do that.
-Question number one.
-Don't point that at me!
Where is Camia Cruz hiding?
I don't know where she is, Emilia!
-Oops, wrong answer.
-Emilia.
[Emilia humming]
[Emilia chuckles]
-[gunshot]
-[Raul screams]
[laughing maniacally]
Oh, I almost got you!
Emilia, what are you trying to do?!
Don't worry.
Let's play this again tomorrow, okay?
You see, I want you to suffer…
slowly, but surely.
-[laughing maniacally]
-You're crazy, Emilia!
Tomorrow again. I'll see you.
-We will play again.
-Emilia, I'm warning you,
once I get out of this, you'll regret it.
Bye, my dear husband!
[Raul] You monster!
You're crazy, Emilia! You're insane.
[door closes]
-What is it, Ivy?
-Come with me, Nanny Carlotta.
You should stay at Mom's house.
You're safer there.
What's happening, Ivy?
Two of our witnesses escaped.
I tried looking for them,
but I couldn't find them.
So I want you to come with me.
I have a bad feeling about this, Nanny.
So you should hide somewhere
else for the time being…
before it's too late.
Okay, I'll just go get my things.
Okay. Hurry, Nanny.
Ivy!
Where are you going?
Let me go with you.
I can help.
-Have mercy on us.
-Please don't hurt my daughter!
I'm begging you! Edward.
Where's your safe house, then?
We have no idea.
-No! Don't hurt our daughter.
-Really?
[Edward] We don't. Really.
-[cocks gun]
-[Esther sobs]
-Edward.
-Camia.
Answer me when I'm asking you!
Where is your safe house?
-Maria!
-Arnaldo! No! Not my daughter!
Okay! Okay! We'll talk!
We'll tell you!
Just don't hurt our daughter!
[Edward] Please! Don't hurt my
daughter! I'm begging you!
[Camia] What?!
Why did they leave the safe house?
I don't know either, Mom.
The CCTV cameras showed
they were talking to someone
on the phone, then they just left.
Ivy, you mentioned you
last heard them
talk to their family, right?
What if the Ardientes have their daughter?
If that's the case,
Esther and Edward are in danger.
Not just them,
but all our witnesses.
[tense music playing]
What's going on?
Have the Ardientes found us?!
Tell us!
We're dead. I bet Edward
and Esther ratted us out.
I hope not!
[gate creaking]
[gunshots]
Move! We're leaving!
-What's happening?
-I knew it!
-Let's go!
-Wait for us!
Break down the door! Leave no one alive!
[gunshots]
Someone's on the run!
[goon] Stand up!
Mayor.
Someone got away.
-Go. Bring them with us.
-Move!
Hurry!
-Did you find him, Madrigal?
-He got away, Mayor.
-He knew where to run.
-It's okay.
Thanks to Esther and Edward,
I know where to find him.
Let's go.
The Ardientes probably know
where the safe house is now.
Mom.
I need to transfer them.
I'll move them to another safe house.
I need to go there now.
Ivy,
I'll go with you.
Okay.
Mom.
-Take care, okay?
-We will.
-Mrs. Camia.
-Take care.
Diego.
Diego, check upstairs.
Ivy, they're not there.
They might've escaped.
Diego, let's look for them.
[phone dings]
TONIO IS ALIVE.
PICK HIM UP FROM HIS HOUSE.
We need to go somewhere. Come on!
[tense music playing]
Okay, everybody. Let's start.
[crew] Rolling in five,
four, three, two… cue!
[Gino] Congressman Ardiente,
thank you for agreeing
to do this interview.
Gino, I should be the one thanking you.
You gave me the opportunity to be heard
by the nation through
your very popular program.
As charismatic as ever, Congressman.
And you aren't bothered by the allegations
against you and your family.
But…
let's focus on the issue here.
Camia Cruz.
Is what she's saying true?
Not a word, Gino. Not a word.
And I will take advantage
of the opportunity to say…
truth be told…
I'm the kind of leader who…
works with transparency.
[Arthur] Please, don't!
-Do it.
-Mayor! Mayor!
[Julio] All my actions,
no matter what they are…
are known to the public.
I don't hide anything from them.
That's why in our town,
all our residents know
that I truly care for them.
I treat them like my own children.
And that's why, in our place,
I am fondly known as "Señor Julio".
You're a monster, Arnaldo!
You'll burn in hell for this!
You're no different from your family!
You're all evil!
[Julio] These are all
allegations, false allegations.
The worst that
she's throwing at me is that…
[screaming]
…that I'm a murderer?
I'll admit, Gino, it hurts to hear that.
Think about it…
What father can stand…
their children…
getting hurt?
[clamoring]
Shut it. Be quiet. Be quiet!
Shut up and be quiet! [fires shots]
[Julio] Or…
what father can…
-I said shut up!
-stand seeing…
[Julio] any of their loved ones in pain?
To top it off…
what father could ever
kill his own children?
[Arnaldo] Finish them off.
[hostages crying]
[gunshot]
[Maria wailing]
[Julio] I don't know any father
like that, Gino.
Because the only father I know how to be…
…is a father full of love.
And to my children in Ardiente.
You know the truth.
Your Señor Julio loves you.
[somber music playing]
[tense music playing]
[tense music continues playing]
Let's go.
[Ivy] Hold on.
What's wrong?
We're surrounded.
-What?
-We can't face them all.
Not yet.
We have to secure Tonio.
[suspenseful music playing]
Get ready.
[Ivy] Let's go!
[Arnaldo firing shots]
[Ivy] Get in!
Back up!
[gunshots]
-Get down! Get down!
-[Arnaldo] Down! I'll drive!
Hurry, Diego!
They're following us.
[fires shots]
Tonio, get down!
Get down, Tonio!
Madrigal, move!
[grunts]
Hurry, Diego!
Over there!
[tires screeching]
Diego, hurry!
[Ivy grunts]
[tires screeching]
Get up!
[Arnaldo] Stay alert.
[tense music playing]
Over here.
Split up.
Over there, Madrigal.
[quietly] Tonio, let's go.
[tense music playing]
Ivy…
you're hurt.
We have to patch it up.
They're here!
[gunshot]
Ivy.
-Jepoy.
-You're hurt.
-I'm fine.
-Get out of here.
Thank you.
[Ivy groans]
What happened?
They got Butch, Mayor.
[Arnaldo scoffs]
We had a casualty?!
Seriously?!
What are you doing?! Hmm?
Answer me! Especially you!
Well?!
You good-for-nothing bastards!
Tonio! If you can hear me!
I…
I will kill you myself!
Hear that?!
Mayor Arnaldo Ardiente will kill you!
And to those who are helping you…
I'll kill you all too!
Take him away.
-Daddy!
-Sweetie!
-Ivy!
-Lily!
What happened?!
We had an encounter with Arnaldo's group.
Mom, where are the other witnesses?
Where are Edward, Esther,
and Arthur? Where are they?
Lily…
Your men called me.
What did they say?
Lily…
they're all dead.
[tense music intensifies]
Dead?
All of them?
[Diego pants]
They're all dead?
[screams]
After everything we've done!
Damn it!
They're dead!
-Lily.
-Those monsters!
I'll kill the Ardientes!
I'll kill them all--
[groans]
Lily! Dear!
Ivy!
-Lily.
-Ivy!
Ivy!
-The congressman is coming!
-There he is. There he is.
Ready the mic and camera.
The congressman is here.
Get over here! Come on. Come on.
Start shooting. Start shooting.
-Good morning, Congressman.
-Good day, Congressman.
-Good morning to all of you.
-Congressman Ardiente…
what can you say about
the accusations pointing you
as the one behind the murder
of Camia Cruz's witnesses?
[chuckles]
Why would I do that?
My family and I know
that if something bad happens
to those witnesses,
we'll be the first to blame.
We are innocent.
Don't you realize that yet?
This is propaganda
from our political rivals.
But I have news for them.
The people of Ardiente aren't stupid.
You can't fool them or us.
And…
to all the bereaved families…
we offer our condolences
first and foremost.
But I also assure you…
that the truth will come out,
and justice will be served.
-Now, if you will excuse me.
-I'm sorry.
Just a follow-up question, Congressman.
-What can you say about…
-Excuse us.
…the cases that will be filed against you?
[Julio] I'm sorry.
-How about…
-I have nothing more…
-Camia Cruz, Congressman?
-to say right now.
How are you going to answer back?
One more statement?
[Emilia] My goodness, Papa.
[Julio] Those gossipmongers.
They won't stop talking
and spreading their rumors.
As soon as they hear about an issue…
they'll talk about it
the whole day at the plaza.
[Julio sighs]
Arnaldo,
you look frazzled. I mean…
Is there something you want to tell me?
Tonio escaped, Grandpa.
We don't know who helped him,
but most probably
they're Camia Cruz's men.
We can't trace who owns the car
he used to escape, either.
Papa, we have to find Tonio!
He knows too much about us!
This is not happening.
Arnaldo…
Clean up your mother's mess.
Not for anything else, but
because you are my best soldier.
Don't fail me.
No Ardiente will rot in jail.
Do what you have to do to silence Tonio.
If there are people who would help him…
put a gun to their heads.
Consider it done.
[Julio] Okay, people. May I remind you?
Please, try to avoid
giving statements to the press.
-Hello, everyone.
-Oh.
-Hi, Ivy!
-I'm sorry, I'm late.
-Hi, Mayor.
-That's okay.
I'm glad you came.
-Good evening, Miss Aguas.
-Congressman. Emilia. Hello.
You missed all the action.
What are you referring to?
The accusations that your family
had all those witnesses killed?
Emilia, I know all the details. Thank you.
Like, um… What did the media say about us?
The usual. That you're all corrupt.
Heartless.
Criminals.
In short…
dirty.
Sorry for asking this, but…
Are you guilty?
Of course not.
[Arnaldo] We play fair.
We didn't have anyone killed.
[Ivy] You have a point, Mr. Mayor.
Only…
a merciless person could do such a thing.
And if you ask me,
they deserve to rot in prison,
or, perhaps, die too.
Right, Congressman?
You couldn't be more right.
Did you know that one
of the witnesses survived?
Yes, Antonio Vidal, my former bodyguard.
So, do you know where he's hiding?
Honestly, Miss Aguas…
we won't waste our time
pondering that issue.
Besides, we're ready for whatever
they're going to throw at us in court.
[Arnaldo] That's right.
I hope you'll be there
during the arraignment.
We need your support.
Of course, Mr. Mayor.
As always, you can count on me.
That's what I like about you.
You never fail us.
So I hope our relationship
continues to improve.
Mr. Mayor…
not so fast.
I haven't even finished
the main course yet.
Let's save that for dessert.
[Ivy] Excuse me.
I need to go to the ladies' room.
Mayor…
Okay. Excuse me.
Go ahead.
-Yes?
-Mayor.
Everything you want to know about Tonio
and his family is in here.
[tense music playing]
Thank you.
-We'll go now, Mayor.
-Okay.
I'll be in my office.
Make sure no one bothers me. Understood?
Yes, Mayor.
[tense music playing]
[chimes]
[knocks]
Ivy?
Ivy, open up…
Ivy, are you there?
Ivy, can we talk?
Um… Just a minute!
[Emilia] Okay.
[suspenseful music playing]
Yes?
Ivy, can we talk?
Sure!
About what?
-Fernandez.
-Madrigal. What is it?
I have something to report to Mayor.
I'm sorry.
He doesn't want to be disturbed.
-He said that?
-Before he went in.
All right.
[Emilia] It's actually about Raul.
Oh. What about him?
It's just between us, okay?
You know, I think…
he's in love with Camia Cruz.
He's obsessed with her.
[tense music playing]
The Camia Cruz?
Yes, the one and only!
To be fair though, Emilia,
Camia Cruz seems nice.
And I find her really beautiful.
It's no wonder Raul is
head over heels in love with her.
Shut up!
It's true!
I'm just being frank.
I don't choose my words
just to gently reassure you.
I'm not like that.
So, what will I do now?
Well, if I were you,
I'd put a leash around his neck
so he couldn't escape
and go sniffing around other women.
-I already did!
-Make it tighter, then.
Ivy, if I do that, what if he
tries to break away even more?
Let him go, then. Just like that.
Let your husband go.
I mean, sure, you can give
that man another chance.
Then another second chance,
a third, a fourth.
Let's see how much you can bear
being a martyr in love.
I guess you're right, Ivy.
You know, I am all that I am.
But I guess, when it comes
to love, it is my weakness.
Love really is stupid.
But, yeah, I'll try that.
Emilia, Raul is the least
of your problems.
You've got bigger fish to fry.
You're facing numerous legal cases.
Like Tonio.
What if he testifies? What will happen?
Can't you do something to keep him quiet?
You know, Ivy?
Honestly, I have no answer for that.
[sighs]
Well, as your friend,
if you get sent to jail,
I'll visit you every day.
Yeah, right!
[giggles]
Emilia, I just wanted
to lighten things up.
Don't be silly.
Trust me. I support you.
And I appreciate that. Let's go.
[chuckles]
[tense music playing]
Love me, Raul.
Please.
Love me back.
That's all I ask of you.
Then take back your threats against Diego.
Show me you love me first.
Mom.
Ivy…
Are you ready for the arraignment?
Honestly, I'm nervous.
What if we lose?
Mom, no.
We can't lose.
We have a high chance of winning this case
because of Tonio's statement against them.
Besides, Dad is watching over us.
I know he will help us.
I'm still willing to make
this marriage work.
You're still my husband.
You're mine.
Get dressed.
Our arraignment is scheduled at 9 AM.
[dramatic music]
-Miss Aguas.
-Mr. Mayor.
I'm glad you made it.
Of course, this is the most
controversial case of the year.
So, I can't miss it.
-How are you, Miss Aguas?
-I'm okay.
Excuse us.
[Raul] Camia.
One stupid move, Raul.
And you'll mourn for Diego.
[tense music playing]
Good morning, Miss Cruz.
Diego. Attorney.
I hope we can clear things out soon.
You know, Miss Cruz…
we aren't your enemies.
Drop the act, Congressman.
No one believes you now.
[court clerk] All rise.
The court is now in session.
The honorable judge
Vincent Legazpi presiding.
[judge bangs gavel]
People of the Philippines versus Emilia
Ardiente-Torillo and Raul Torillo.
Criminal case number 3246950
for conspiracy to commit rape,
case number 3246783 for attempted murder,
and case number 3256109
for illegal detention.
Let's proceed.
[tense music playing]
The prosecution calls
Mr. Antonio Vidal to the witness stand.
Please raise your right hand.
Do you solemnly swear to tell the truth,
and nothing but the truth?
I do.
Mr. Vidal…
can you please tell the court
what your connection
to the Ardiente family was?
I used to be a bodyguard for
former governor Emilia Torillo.
So, as Mrs. Torillo's former bodyguard,
what were your duties?
My duty was to ensure
her safety and security…
and to protect her and her family
from anyone who threatened them.
Was it also your duty
to obey whatever
Mrs. Torillo ordered you to do?
Yes, your Honor.
Did you do everything she told you to?
She was my boss, your Honor.
Of course, I would carry out her orders.
Even if it was to kill innocent people?
If she told me to,
I'd do it.
Mr. Vidal, did former governor
Emilia Torillo
order you to rape and kill Camia Cruz,
wife of Atty. Dante Cruz,
a critic of the Ardientes?
[tense music playing]
I repeat.
Did the former governor order you
to rape and kill Camia Cruz?
No, your Honor.
[tense music playing]
[Emilia] Camia. Camia, darling.
Even if you have me killed now,
your husband will never love you!
So you really want more?!
[Ivy] Emilia, that's enough!
[Emilia] You're right about Ivy.
She's just playing with us.
I don't know if she's
only just convinced Diego
or if they've always been accomplices.
[Julio] We can't trust anyone anymore.
I want you to keep an eye on Madrigal.
You have to see this.
Good work, Arnaldo.
We finally caught the rat.
[theme music playing]